checkster.com 2018-09-17

# Privacy | Checkster

**[English](https://www.checkster.com/privacy) | [Français](https://www.checkster.com/privacy-francais) | [Español](https://www.checkster.com/privacy-espanol) | [Nederlands |](https://www.checkster.com/privacybeleid-dutch) [Italiano](https://www.checkster.com/privacy-italian) | [日本語](https://www.checkster.com/privacy-japanese) | [한국어](https://www.checkster.com/privacy-korean) | 中文  **|  Português****

**1\. Policy Statement**

1.1   
Any information collected, held or otherwise Processed by Checkster, Inc., 926 Diablo Ave #305, Novato, CA 94947, info@checkster.com or + 1415 892 1307 ( **"Checkster"** or  **"We"** ) relating to any individual is subject to this policy. This policy sets out (i) the rights of individuals with respect to their personal information and (ii) the responsibilities of Checkster to access and use such personal information. 

1.2   
The requirements of this policy are in addition to, not in substitution of, any other requirements under the applicable data protection laws and regulations. In case of conflict between the applicable data protection laws and regulations and the provisions of this privacy policy, the applicable data protection laws and regulations shall prevail.

1.3   
Checkster may amend this policy at any point in time. Please check this policy periodically on http://www.checkster.com/privacy to inform yourself of any changes.

**2\. Definitions**

2.1   
**Data Controller**  means the organization which determines the purposes and means of the Processing of Personal Data for which, and the manner in which, any Personal Data is Processed. Checkster will be acting as Data Controller when:

(a) Processing Personal Data for Purpose 3.1(c) and, in certain circumstances, for Purpose 3.1(b); and

(b) in any event when the Data Subject is using Checkster's services for its own purposes.

2.2   
**Data Subjects**  for the purpose of this policy include all identified or identifiable natural persons about whom Checkster holds Personal Data. 

2.3   
**Data Processor**  means the organization which Processes Personal Data on behalf of the Data Controller. When Processing Personal Data for Purpose 3.1(a) and, in certain circumstances, for Purpose 3.1(b), Checkster will be acting as Data Processor on behalf of Checkster's customer unless the Data Subject is using Checkster's services for its own purposes.

2.4   
**Personal Data**  is any data relating to a living individual which allows the individual to be identified, whether from that data alone, or in combination with other information which is in the possession, or likely to come into the possession of Checkster. A description of the Personal Data is set out in Schedule 1;

2.5   
**Processing**  means any operation or set of operations which is performed upon Personal Data or sets of Personal Data, whether or not by automatic means, such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaption or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure or destruction of Personal Data.

2.6   
**Sensitive Data**  means, among others, Personal Data revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade-union membership, and the Processing of data concerning health or sex life. 

**3\. Collection and Use of Personal Data**

3.1   
Checkster may Process Personal Data for the following purposes, upon instruction of the Data Controller (the Purposes):

(a) In order to provide its services;

(b) Operate, administer and optimize its website and to diagnose problems with its website;

(c) Direct marketing purposes so that Checkster may provide the Data Subject with information about products and services that may be of interest to the Data Subject. The Processing of Personal Data for direct marketing purposes will only be done, after explicit consent of the Data Subject. 

3.2   
Personal Data relating to any user of Checkster's services ( **Checkster user** ) will be collected from the Checkster user himself, from Checkster's customer (if the Checkster user is not himself a Checkster customer for his own purposes) or from any individual who has been designated by the Checkster user as a possible rater. 

3.3   
Personal Data relating to raters will be collected from the raters themselves or from a Checkster user.

3.4   
Checkster shall only Process Personal Data to the extent that is relevant for the Purposes. Given that no Sensitive Data are required to achieve any of the Purposes Checkster will not Process Sensitive Data and Checkster invites anyone using its services (whether as a Checkster user, as a rater or otherwise) to refrain from sharing with Checkster any Sensitive Data about themselves or other individuals.

3.5 Checkster may offer functionality from third parties by redirecting you to the third party's website. While visiting the third party site, your privacy choices and the data you share with the third party will be subject to the third party's privacy policy, and not subject to Checkster's privacy policy. Checkster will provide a clear disclaimer when directing you to third party websites where Checkster's privacy policy does not apply, and you will have the option to continue on Checkster without using the third party.

**4\. Timely Processing**

4.1   
Checkster shall retain Personal Data in a manner consistent with the applicable data protection laws and regulations. In any event, Personal Data shall not be kept longer than is necessary for the Purposes, unless the data are required to be kept longer by law. If Checkster is acting as a Data Processor, the duration of this term will be determined by the Data Controller.

**5\. Rights of the Data Subject**

5.1   
Each Data Subject has the right to access the Personal Data that the Data Controller holds about him or her and to request rectification or erasure of the Personal Data or restriction of Processing of Personal Data concerning the Data Subject or to object to the Processing of such Personal Data as well as the right to data portability. If Checkster is not the Data Controller:

(a) Checkster will pass the request on to the Data Controller; or

(b) the Data Subject may also contact the Data Controller directly. The contact details of the Data Controller will be mentioned in the initial e-mail that the Data Subject receives, inviting him or her to use the services of Checkster.

5.2   
The Data Subject has a right to lodge a complaint to the competent supervisory authority if he or she deems that Checkster is Processing his or her Personal Data in violation of any applicable data protection laws and regulations. However, Checkster strongly encourages Data Subjects to contact Checkster for any complaints or queries (see section 10 for our contact details) prior to lodging any complaints to the competent supervisory authority. 

5.3   
The Data Subject shall have the right to object, on grounds relating to his or her particular situation, at any time to the Processing of Personal Data concerning him or her. The Data Controller shall no longer Process the Personal Data unless the Data Controller can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the Processing which override the interests, rights and freedoms of the Data Subject or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims. When Checkster is not the Data Controller:

(a) any objection to the Processing of Personal Data received by Checkster will be passed on to the Data Controller; or

(b) the Data Subject may also contact the Data Controller directly to object to the Processing of his or her Personal Data. The contact details of the Data Controller will be mentioned in the initial e-mail that the Data Subject receives inviting him or her to use the services of Checkster.

5.4    
If we Process Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, the Data Subject shall have the right to object at any time to the Processing of Personal Data concerning him or her for such marketing purposes.

**6\. Data Security**

6.1   
Checkster shall ensure that appropriate technical and organizational security measures are taken against unlawful or unauthorized Processing of Personal Data, and against the misuse, destruction, disclosure, acquisition, accidental loss of, or damage to Personal Data.

**7\. Disclosure of Personal Data**

7.1   
If it is appropriate to achieve any of the Purposes Checkster may share the Personal Data with the following categories of recipients:

(a) Checkster will disclose Personal Data with Checkster's customers. 

(b) Checkster may share Personal Data with a subsidiary or parent company.

(c) Checkster may also share the Personal Data with external providers of IT related services.

**8\. Transfer of Personal Data to a third country**

8.1   
Since Checkster is located outside the European Economic Area, Checkster and Checkster's customer have ensured that any transfer of Personal Data will be conducted in compliance with the applicable data protection laws and regulations. Checkster and Checkster's European customer have concluded a contract (or signed a Model Clause) for the transfer of Personal Data to non-EU/EEA countries, containing the standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission. A copy of this contract is available upon request.

8.2   
Checkster shall not transfer Personal Data to countries outside the European Economic Area that do not provide an adequate level of protection unless such transfer is necessary for the Purposes, in which case Checkster shall ensure that the transfer will be conducted in compliance with the applicable data protection laws and regulations.

Global Clients will either store their data in Europe or sign a Model Clause with Checkster.

8.3 General Data Protection Regulation European Representative

Pursuant to Article 27 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), Checkster Inc. has appointed European Data Protection Office ([EDPO](https://www.smartcertificate.com/SmartCertificate/Default.aspx?OUzRIZdibcSGkmHiWcpbWL0TkPbVNB9Ee6iPHJvG3moWLgZsS9FlfuURGwlT4Q%2b9)) as its GDPR representative in the EU. You can contact EDPO regarding matters pertaining to the GDPR by:

  * Sending an email to [privacy@edpo.brussels](mailto:privacy@edpo.brussels)
  * Using EDPO’s online request form at <https://www.edpo.brussels/contact>
  * Writing to EDPO at Avenue Huart Hamoir 71, 1030 Brussels, Belgium

For the purpose of compliance with EU data protection laws our data protection officer is CMS Debacker:

CMS Debacker cvba/scrl  
Tel      +32 2 743 69 00  
Fax     +32 2 743 69 01  
Mobile +32 497 535 225  
[office@cms-db.com  
](mailto:office@cms-db.com)Chaussée de la Hulpe 178  
1170 Brussels  
Belgium

For any questions or concerns about Checkster’s Privacy Policy or about Checkster’s data handling practices, you may contact CMS Debacker.

**9\. Cookies**

9.1   
Our website makes use of small text files called "cookies". These cookies are small files that are saved on the hard drive of your computer when you visit our website. By making use of cookies, Checkster is able to provide you a better overall website experience.

9.2   
The following cookies are used on this website:

— User-input cookies: these are session cookies that are used to keep track of the user's input. They are required in order for the website to work properly. They are temporary files, which are erased when you close your browser. 

— Authentication cookies: these are session cookies that are used to identify the user once he or she has logged in. These cookies are needed to allow users to authenticate themselves on successive visits to the website and gain access to authorized content. They are temporary files, which are erased when you close your browser. 

— Google Analytics: Google Analytics is used to track visitors’ usage of the website (how much time spent on the website, the areas visited, etc.). This helps us understand how visitors interact with our website, which allows us to improve the overall functionality. Google Analytics is not necessary for the proper functioning of the website.

Checkster does not use any third-party cookies or flash cookies.

9.3   
You may refuse our use of cookies at any point in time. It is sufficient for you to configure your browser settings to limit or exclude the use of cookies, or to delete the cookies that have already been placed on your computer. However, in such case, you might not be able to use certain functionalities on our website.  
Cookie settings may vary from one browser to another. The below hyperlinks provide further guidance on how to disable the use of cookies on your browser, and/or on how to delete cookies:

— Chrome: https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en;  
— Internet Explorer: http://windows.microsoft.com/en-US/windows-vista/Block-or-allow-cookies and http://windows.microsoft.com/en-us/internet-explorer/delete-manage-cookies#ie=ie-11-win-7;  
— Mozilla Firefox: https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences?redirectlocale=en-US&redirectslug=Enabling+and+disabling+cookies and https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored;  
— Safari: [http://support.apple.com/kb/index?page=search&fac=all&q=cookies%20safari](http://support.apple.com/kb/index?page=search&fac=all&q=cookies%20safari)).

Click here to read more about our Cookie Policy: http://www.checkster.com/cookie-policy

**10\. Contact**

10.1   
For any privacy issues, questions or complaints concerning the application of this Policy or to exercise your rights of access or rectification within the context of this Policy, individuals may contact the Checkster support team at [support@checkster.com](mailto:support@checkster.com).

10.2

If, for whatever reason, you believe you have been subject to a personal data breach through Checkster, you may submit details to info@checkster.com.

**Schedule 1: DESCRIPTION OF PERSONAL DATA**  
We may collect the following Personal Data:

\- IP Address;  
\- Full name;  
\- Postal Address;  
\- Phone Number;  
\- E-mail Address;  
\- Financial information (i.e. Credit card numbers or passwords);  
\- For raters: title, current employer, past employer and relation with candidates and any other Personal Data that might be provided in a rater review;  
\- For employment verification: past salary of candidate, reason for leaving and any other Personal Data that might be provided in a rater review;  
\- Demographic information (i.e. information that you submit, or that we collect, that is neither personal information nor financial information, this may include, zip code, postal code, username, purchase history information, browsing history information, searching history information, registration history information.

Privacy Policy last updated MAY 10, 2018
